Rafał Skwara

Address ul. Afrykańska 03-966 Warsaw Poland

Phone +48695729757

E-mail rafal.skwara@gmail.com

Born 1988/05/21

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/rafał-skwara-75746259/



I am a journalism graduate with analytic and computer skills up my sleeve. My goal is to find an interesting IT/programming role so I can grow thanks to cooperation with experienced developers. I want to put my skills to a test and gain some new ones along with some valuable experience. I seek an opportunity to prove I can be a remarkable asset to any company.

Links

https://rafalskwara.github.io/storefront/ - React based app, still under development

https://rafalskwara.github.io/spacex/ - React SPA using SpaceX open API

https://github.com/RafalSkwara - my github account

https://codepen.io/rafalskwara/ - my Codepen account

Skills

HTML5

CSS3: positioning, styling, animations and more

JavaScript, jQuery: DOM traversal and manipulation, simple algorithms, RESTful API, OOP basics

React.js, React Router, Redux - beginner to intermediate

Dev Tools: git basics, Gulp; proficient in Sass and Pug/Jade, npm

Video and graphics editing: Photoshop, Premiere Pro, Resolve

Work Experience

2017/11 WSiP, ETP department

ETP Specialist

Front end programming: creating interactive screens and games for an Electron based application using HTML5, CSS, vanilla JavaScript, jQuery and jQuery UI and various other JS libraries. Designing user interactions. Debugging. Applications were made for biggest Polish educational publishing house, mainly meant for children aged 3-10 and were distributed between thousands of Polish primary schools and nurseries.

Some of the projects include for instance a drawing app with HTML Canvas API and a map viewer with zooming and dragging features.

2017/08 - 2017/10 WSiP, E-Marketing Department

Junior E-Marketing Specialist

Coding HTML e-mails, creating and running mailing campaigns using Freshmail and Company's own CRM software. Creating content for the corporate website and updating the website according to Company's marketing plan. I was a part of a team that created comprehensive online campaigns for WSiP.

2014/12 - 2017/04 Clipper Logistics Plc, Worsley, Manchester

Goods In Worker, FLT Driver

Taking care of deliveries in a logistic company's warehouse. Accepting goods, quality checks, liaising with customer's HQ in London (Excel, Google Docs, MS NAV). Driving FLT Reach Truck.

2014/10 - 2014/11 D

DHL, Manchester

temporary admin role

A temporary role in one of the biggest companies in the logistics industry. The job involved administrating part of parcel delivery system, contacting drivers and customers about their deliveries and rescheduling them as needed. This role was a huge boost for my English skills.

2014/06 - 2014/09

Shioness Ltd., Manchester

brand manager

Temporary role with a new company involving helping with technical issues and building the brand's image online. I bought and managed company's domains, populated its online storefront with product data (WordPress), started and managed social media profiles and the company blog, took care of selling process (both generic and eBay). I used Google Analytics and AdWords. The role expired after three months.

Education

2007/09 - 2010/07

University of Warsaw, journalism and social communications, Bachelors

Key skills gained:

- the role of communications, its core structure and how it's affected by psychological and sociological factors,
- critical information research,
- basic knowledge of Public Relations,
- journalist skills.

2016/11

FreeCodeCamp, Front End Developer course (ongoing)

Comprehensive and practical online course created by an NGO. The course provides deep understanding of HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery along with basic JavaScript and REST API. Some projects available on my CodePen profile:

http://codepen.io/rafalskwara/

2016/05 - 2016/07

Codecademy, front end path (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React)

The course provided me with some basic knowledge concerning a few of the most important web technologies. It was a foundation upon which I've been building new skills ever since I completed it.

Languages

English

fluent (B2 certified + 3 years spent in the UK)

Spanish

beginner

Polish

native speaker

Hobbies and Interests

Learning to play an electric guitar - which helps develop manual skills and analytical approach to music while being massively relaxing.

Reading: non-fiction - which partially satiates my urge to learn new things and broadens my horizons.

New technologies - mostly (but not only) related to the Internet.

Football, especially Premier League.